<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io</id>
    <title>Micah的日常BB Channel</title>
    <updated>2021-12-07T14:57:50.720Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>言者无罪，闻者足戒。</subtitle>
    <logo>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, Micah的日常BB Channel</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/21 ––– 2021/11/28]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211121-20211128/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211121-20211128/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-29T00:02:29.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="weekly-morning-newswire-20211121-20211128">Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/21 ––– 2021/11/28</h1>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, in today's Weekly Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>A SUV stormed into a Christmas Parade in Waukesha, Wisconsin, results 6 deaths and more than 60 injured.</li>
<li>The creator of RenRen Subtitle Group was sentenced to 3 and a half year in jail, with a 1.5 million CNY fine.</li>
<li>Confirmed cases of Omicron covid variant bursted in Southern Africa, 1 case in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>South Korea's former president, Jeon Du-Hwan, died at age 90.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="6-dead-and-more-than-60-injured-after-a-suv-charged-into-a-christmas-parade-in-waukesha-wisconsin">6 dead and more than 60 injured after a SUV charged into a Christmas Parade in Waukesha, Wisconsin.</h2>
<p>A red SUV charged into a Christmas Parade which takes place at Waukesha, Wisconsin at November 21, and more than 60 people are injured and 6 people are dead, including 1 6-year-old child. The suspect Darrell Brooks Jr. was charged with crimes since 1999, and the police had draw 5 first-degree charges of intentional homicide against him for the SUV storming. 4 women aged between 52-79 and a 81-year-old man was killed in the incident, and all the women victims were belong to a local Dancing Grannies club. An 8-year-old was injured at first but died on Tuesday (November 23). Waukesha's Police Chief Dan Thompson said that there's no evidence stating that the event is a terrorist attack nor did suspect knew anybody in the parade before. ([AP] Scott Bauer, Michael Balsamo, Mike Householder; Sara Burnett, Kathleen Foody, Tim Sullivan)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Police stand near toppled chairs lining W. Main St. in downtown Waukesha, Wis., after an SUV drove into a parade of Christmas marchers, Sunday, Nov. 21, 2021. (John Hart/Wisconsin State Journal via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/1000-2.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>People gather in Waukesha's Cutler Park for a candlelight vigil for those affected by the Waukesha Christmas Parade tragedy, Monday, Nov. 22, 2021 in Waukesha, Wis.. The event was hosted by the Association of Waukesha Congregations with participation by the Brookfield - Elm Grove Interfaith Network (BEGIN) and the Interfaith Conference of Greater Milwaukee.(Scott Ash/Milwaukee Journal-Sentinel via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="the-creator-of-renren-subtitle-group-was-sentenced-42-months-in-jail-and-a-15-million-cny-fine">The creator of RenRen subtitle group was sentenced 42 months in jail and a 1.5 million CNY fine.</h2>
<p>Liang Yongping, head of Renren Film and Television Subtitle Group, was sentenced to 42 months in the first instance by the Shanghai Third Intermediate People's Court on the 22nd and fined 1.5 million CNY. The court stated that his conduct of instigating employees to develop the site and application of RenRen Subtitle Group, and downloading, translating, producing subtitles of unauthorized film productions and spreading them to the site members was considered as serious infringement. A total of 6.83 million people have purchased RenRen Subtitle Group's membership, and the site contains up to 32824 unauthorized film production copies. ([Lianhe Zaobao])</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/16381002652298.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The comment under the report of RenRen Subtitle Group infringement case by user @财经网 at Weibo, the comments was filled with the appreciation for RenRen's service, and the doubt of justification for other plagiarisms done by other domestic TV shows and film production. (Screenshot by Micah)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="a-new-covid-variant-b11529-omicron-made-considerable-impact-in-southern-africa-british-scientists-claimed-it-as-worst-ever">A new covid variant B.1.1.529 (Omicron) made considerable impact in Southern Africa, British scientists claimed it as &quot;worst ever&quot;.</h2>
<p>WHO has given the name &quot;Omicron&quot; to the new covid variant B.1.1.529, which first appears in Botswana at November 11, and causing more confirmed cases in South Africa. Currently there's 77 confirmed cases in Gauteng Province, South Africa (90% of them was caused by the new Omicron variant), 4 in Botswana, and 2 in Hong Kong. Hong Kong's Center of Health Protection said that the new variant was brought by a 36-year-old male who has flown to Hong Kong from South Africa at November 11, and it was passed down to a 62-year-old Canadian male living at the next room of Regal Airport Hotel. Tulio de Oliveira, the director of Center of Epidemic Response &amp; Innovation in South Africa(CERI), said that the mutations of the Omicron variant's strains were very high, and considered very different to the other variants. Almost all Asian stock markets fell across the board at November 26, after hearing the news on Omicron variant. ([Lianhe Zaobao]; [BBC])</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/hkgov-omicron-pr-eng.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The press release issued by Hong Kong government on the new Omicron variant. (Screenshot by Micah)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="jeon-du-hwan-전두환-south-koreas-former-president-died-of-age-90-on-november-23">Jeon Du-Hwan (전두환), South Korea's former president, died of age 90 on November 23.</h2>
<p>Former South Korea's President, Jeon Du-Hwan (전두환), died at his own house on November 23. The South Korean people said that they are angry because Jeon doesn't regret and apologize to the public before he died. His wife, Yi Sun-Ja (이순자), apologized for her husband instead on Jeon's funeral, which was hosted at Severance Hospital, Seoul on November 27. The South Korean government stated on November 23 that they will not host a national funeral for Jeon, and it is considered as the first time not making a national funeral for a former president ever since the national funeral was introduced in South Korea. Jeon Du-Hwan (전두환) was served as the 11th and 12th president of South Korea by initiating military coup for seizing power after the former president, Park Chung-Hee (박정희), was assassinated, and he was notoriously known for his brutal crackdown on 1980's Kwangju Democratic Movement (광주 민주화 운동), which caused 4900 deaths of citizens. ([Lianhe Zaobao]; [Yonhap News Agency])</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/ACK20211127000100881_01_i_P4.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>South Korea's former president, Jeon Du-Hwan's funeral was hosted on November 27 at Seoul's Severance Hospital. His hearse was leaving the funeral parlor. (via Yonhap News Agency)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the ideas, meanings etc. that are presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="一周早间要闻-20211121-20211128">一周早间要闻 2021/11/21 ––– 2021/11/28</h1>
<p>各位听众及观众早安！以下是这一周的焦点消息：</p>
<ul>
<li>一辆轿车冲进沃基肖市的一场圣诞游行，造成6人死亡及超过60人受伤</li>
<li>河南30名中学生在吃过校内午餐后呕吐，校长哭诉：「送餐公司是教育局招标的」</li>
<li>人人影视字幕组负责人因侵权被判42个月</li>
<li>南非「奥米克戎」变体感染人数急剧增长，香港有2例感染</li>
<li>韩国前总统全斗焕逝世</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="一辆轿车冲进沃基肖市的一场圣诞游行造成6人死亡及超过60人受伤">一辆轿车冲进沃基肖市的一场圣诞游行，造成6人死亡及超过60人受伤</h2>
<p>一辆红色的SUV于11月21日冲进在威斯康辛州沃基肖市的一场圣诞庆祝游行，造成超过60名人员受伤以及包括一名6岁孩童在内的6人死亡。嫌犯Darrell Brooks Jr.曾自1999年来犯下16项罪行，且地方警察已对圣诞节游行一事对他提起5项一级蓄意杀人指控。4名年龄介于52至79岁之间的女子及一名81岁的男子于袭击中死亡，且四名女性死者均属于一个地方的老人舞蹈俱乐部。一名8岁的孩童在周一被撞伤之后于周二死亡。沃基肖市警长Dan Thompson称目前没有任何证据表明这是一次恐怖袭击，且嫌犯也未曾与游行中的人群产生过联系。（引述美联社Scott Bauer，Michael Balsamo，Mike Householder及Sara Burnett，Kathleen Foody，Tim Sullivan消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>在一辆SUV于2021年11月21日星期日冲撞一场圣诞游行的队伍之后，警察站在威斯康星州沃基肖市中心西主街两旁倒塌的椅子附近。(John Hart/Wisconsin State Journal 经由美联社)</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="7"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/1000-2.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>2021年11月22日星期一，人们聚集在威斯康星州沃基肖的沃基肖卡特勒公园，为受沃克沙圣诞游行悲剧影响的人举行烛光守夜。该活动由沃基肖会众协会主办，Brookfield - Elm Grove 宗教间联络网（BEGIN）和大密尔沃基宗教间会议参加了活动。(Scott Ash/Milwaukee Journal-Sentinel 经由美联社)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="河南30名学生在吃过校内午餐后呕吐校长哭诉公司是教育局招标的">河南30名学生在吃过校内午餐后呕吐，校长哭诉：「公司是教育局招标的」</h2>
<p>河南封丘县赵岗镇戚城中学的30名学生在食用过校内的午饭后出现呕吐及腹泻现象。根据河南电视台《都市报道》记者所拍摄的视频表示，家长在事发后选择给自家孩子带餐，并集体在校门口阻止送餐公司车辆驶入校园。随后记者采访到学校校长表示，校长在接受采访的时候流下眼泪，称「送餐公司是教育局招标的」且「自己想换，但换不动」，并称「自己不是一个好校长」。记者在校门口询问送餐公司人员得知他们所属的公司为北京志宏恒达商贸有限公司，其在之前已因违反相关环境规定而被处罚两次。当地县教体局副局长王念四、县教体局食管办负责人吕勇、县市场监管局副局长闫文峰及食品经营安全监督管理股负责人王宝帅均已被停职并立案调查。（引述联合早报及河南电视台《都市报道》消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="8"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/acc7d5cacf8a4be985e81c122d56ba1f.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>河南电视台《都市报道》对此事件报道的微博截图</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="人人影视字幕组负责人因侵权被判42个月并处罚150万元罚款">人人影视字幕组负责人因侵权被判42个月，并处罚150万元罚款</h2>
<p>人人影视字幕组负责人梁永平于22日被上海市第三中级人民法院一审宣判42个月的刑期，并处以150万元的罚款。其因指使员工开发“人人影视字幕组”网站及客户端，并大量的从境外下载、翻译、制作并对站内会员进行分享的行为已构成严重侵权。经法院审计，人人影视字幕组网站及客户端内共有32824部未授权影视作品，并含有683万会员。（引述联合早报消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="9"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/16381002652298.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>微博用户 @财经网 对人人影视字幕组侵权一案报道的微博下的评论，许多网友对人人影视字幕组以往的陪伴表示感谢，有些网友则对国内影视作品抄袭的正当性表示质疑。（Micah截图）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="南非奥米克戎遍体助长新增病例英国科学家史上最糟糕">南非「奥米克戎」遍体助长新增病例，英国科学家：史上最糟糕</h2>
<p>南非邻国博茨瓦纳于11月11日发现一种名为B.1.1.529的新型冠状病毒变体，并在近期被世界卫生组织以第15个希腊字母「奥米克戎」命名。截止到目前，南非已有77名新冠确诊病例，其中90%为新变体病例；同时博兹瓦纳含有4例，香港含有2例。香港卫生防护中心称一名36的男子在11月11日从南非飞向香港时将「奥米克戎」变体带到香港，且在富豪机场酒店传染给一名住在隔壁的62岁加拿大裔男子。南非疫情应对及创新中心主任Tulio de Oliveira称「奥米克戎」新变体含有极高的突变量，且与其他变体非常不同。在26日听到有关「奥米克戎」新变体的新闻后，所有亚洲股市全线下跌。（引述联合早报及BBC消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="10"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/hkgov-omicron-pr-cn.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>香港政府对「奥米克戎」变体发布的新闻公报。（Micah截图）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="南韩前总统全斗焕于11月23日逝世享年90岁">南韩前总统全斗焕于11月23日逝世，享年90岁</h2>
<p>南韩前总统全斗焕 (전두환) 于11月23日在其私宅中逝世，南韩民众因其从未在生前对公众进行忏悔或道歉而感到愤怒。全斗焕的葬礼于11月27日在首尔世福兰斯医院举行，其夫人李顺子 (이순자) 为其丈夫代为向公众道歉。南韩政府青瓦台于11月23日声明将不会为全斗焕举行国葬，为韩国引进国葬以来首次不为逝世总统举行国葬。全斗焕于韩国前总统朴正熙 (박정희) 遇刺后发动「双十二政变」，借此上位任第11届及12届大韩民国总统。其在任期内对1980年代的光州民主化运动 (광주 민주화 운동) 进行的血腥镇压让其饱受争议及谩骂，镇压一共造成了4900名市民及学生死亡。（引述联合早报及韩联社消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="11"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0008/ACK20211127000100881_01_i_P4.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>南韩前总统朴正熙的葬礼于11月27号在首尔世福兰斯医院举行，其灵车正在离开殡仪馆。（经由韩联社）</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>免责声明：</em></p>
<p><em>所有新闻文章之选段之版权归于原作者、摄影师等作者及工作人员所有。本站呈现之新闻文章之选段并不代表本站同意之选段之立场及观点。</em></p>
<hr>
<p>关注我们以每周接收客观、准确的国际和国内新闻！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/15 ––– 2021/11/21]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211115-20211121/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211115-20211121/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-21T15:45:19.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="weekly-morning-newswire-20211115-20211121">Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/15 ––– 2021/11/21</h1>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, in today's Weekly Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>Suspect for U of Chicago sentenced for first-degree murder, court rejected bail.</li>
<li>Lv. 5.0 earthquake shook in Jiangsu, Shanghai felt the shaking.</li>
<li>Apple announced Self Service Repair for individual consumers.</li>
<li>A bomb exploded near Liverpool Women's Hospital, taxi driver locked the attacker in the vehicle.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="gunner-for-killing-zheng-shaoxiong-was-accused-of-first-degree-murder-and-no-bail">Gunner for killing Zheng Shaoxiong was accused of first-degree murder, and no bail.</h2>
<p>Alton Spann, the suspect that accused of hijacking and shooting at the University of Chicago, was officially accused of first-degree murder by the local prosecutors at Cook County, Chicago. Alton was also blamed for killing a Chinese overseas student, Zheng Shaoxiong, in November 9, 2:00 p.m. CST. The court has rejected the bail for Alton, and the death of Zheng triggered strong response from the Chinese consulate general and ambassador. The memorial ceremony for Zheng was hosted on November 18 at University of Chicago, with the presence of Zheng's mother. His mother mourned that &quot;her first visit to a foreign country is to attend his son's memorial meeting&quot; and &quot;the suspect must be punished hard&quot;. (Lianhe Zaobao)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Students and friends of Shaoxiong &quot;Dennis&quot; Zheng stop by a memorial on Wednesday, Nov. 10, 2021 in Chicago. Police say Zheng was fatally shot while on the sidewalk shortly before 2 p.m. Tuesday. The slaying of the Chinese college student fatally shot during an armed robbery near the University of Chicago campus prompted the school's president to call for city officials to treat violence as a “public health crisis.” (Madeline Kenney/Chicago Sun-Times via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="lv5-earthquake-took-place-near-jiangsu-seawaters-shanghai-residents-felt-shaking">Lv.5 earthquake took place near Jiangsu seawaters, Shanghai residents felt shaking.</h2>
<p>A lv.5 earthquake occurred near the seawaters at Yancheng, Jiangsu Province at November 17. The quake's origin reached a depth of 17 kilometers and located at latitude 33.50 degrees North and longitude 121.19 East, with the nearest distance of 45 kilometers to the sea shore. The shaking was felt among the entire Jiangsu province, with the strongest shake at Yancheng and Nantong. Residents in Nanjing and Shanghai have also felt the shake, and some ran out for seeking safety. (Lianhe Zaobao; Caixin)</p>
<h2 id="apple-announced-self-service-repair-for-individual-consumers-starting-from-iphone-12-and-iphone-13">Apple announced Self Service Repair for individual consumers, starting from iPhone 12 and iPhone 13.</h2>
<p>Apple announced Self Service Repair at November 17, which allows giving individual consumers parts, tools and manuals for repairing the Apple products by themselves: starting with iPhone 12 and iPhone 13, and M1-chip powered Mac computers in future. The service will begin first in the U.S. around early 2022 and will be promoted to additional countries in 2022. Apple said that this service will first start on the commonly serviced modules such as iPhone display, battery and camera, and the additional repair will be added throughout the next year. Apple's chief operating officer, Jeff Williams, said that &quot;creating greater access to Apple genuine parts gives our customers even more choice if a repair is needed&quot; and &quot;in the past three years, Apple has nearly doubled the number of service locations with access to Apple genuine parts, tools, and training, and now we’re providing an option for those who wish to complete their own repairs.&quot; (Apple Newsroom)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/Apple_Self-Service-Repair_hero_11172021.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The poster shown for illustrating Apple's Self Service Repair at Apple Newsroom.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="a-bomb-detonated-near-liverpool-womens-hospital-within-a-taxi-cab-locked-by-the-driver">A bomb detonated near Liverpool Women's Hospital, within a taxi cab locked by the driver.</h2>
<p>Emad Al Swealmeen, a refugee flew from Syria, detonated a bomb in locked taxi cab near Liverpool Women's Hospital at Remembrance Sunday. The taxi driver David Perry locked the door and ran after he spot the bomb. The explosion instantly killed Al Swealmeen and caused injuries to David Perry. The UK terror threat level was raised to &quot;severe&quot; after the blast take place, and David Perry received praises from government officials and online donations from Liverpool citizens for replenishing his loss at the bomb attack. His wife Mrs. Perry claimed that &quot;it was truly a miracle&quot; for escaping the explosion, and &quot;he certainly had some guardian angels looking over him.&quot; (BBC, Samantha Jagger)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/0_liverpool-womens-hospital5.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The cab of David Perry after the bomb was detonated. (via Liverpool Echo)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the ideas, meanings etc. that are presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="一周早间要闻-20211115-20211121">一周早间要闻 2021/11/15 ––– 2021/11/21</h1>
<p>各位观众及听众早安，以下是这一周所发生的要闻：</p>
<ul>
<li>芝加哥大学枪击案凶手被控一级谋杀，法院拒绝其保释。</li>
<li>江苏发生5.0级地震，上海和南京均有震感。</li>
<li>苹果推出自助维修计划，可向个人消费者提供零件及手册。</li>
<li>英国利物浦发生自杀式炸弹袭击，出租车司机将凶手锁在车内避免危机扩散。</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="芝加哥大学枪击案凶手被控一级谋杀法院拒绝其保释">芝加哥大学枪击案凶手被控一级谋杀，法院拒绝其保释</h2>
<p>一名被指控于芝加哥大学进行抢劫及枪击的嫌犯，Alton Spann，近日被芝加哥库克显州检察官指控一级谋杀罪、持枪抢劫罪及两项非法使用武器罪，并被法院拒绝保释。Alton此前于美国芝加哥时间9日下午两点抢劫一名名叫郑少雄（音译）的中国留学生，并朝其胸部开枪。郑少雄中枪之后被送往医院，但因伤势过重去世。郑少雄的死讯引发中国互联网的热烈讨论及中国驻芝加哥总领事馆和驻美大使秦刚的强烈回应，其母亲于18日现身芝加哥大学出席追悼会。她称「儿子曾说要带自己看世界，但没想到第一次出国竟是参加他的葬礼」并要求「严惩凶手」。（引述联合早报消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>学生及郑少雄的朋友于2021年11月10日在芝加哥参与他的追悼会。警方称郑少雄在9日下午两点左右在人行道遭到致命枪击。这位中国大学生在芝加哥大学校园附近的武装抢劫中被枪杀，此事件促使该校校长呼吁市政官员将暴力视为「公共卫生危机」。（Madeline Kenny/Chicago Sun-Times 经由美联社）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="江苏发生50级地震上海和南京均有震感">江苏发生5.0级地震，上海和南京均有震感</h2>
<p>江苏省盐城市附近水域于17日发生5.0级地震，震中位于北纬33.50度及东经121.19度。震源深达17公里且离海岸线最近距离为45公里。盐城市及南通市伴有最强烈震感，且震感波及到全江苏省以及南京市与上海市。一些居民在发生地震之后迅速跑出建筑物以寻求安全。（引述联合早报及财新网消息）</p>
<h2 id="苹果推出自助维修计划可向个人消费者提供零件及手册">苹果推出自助维修计划，可向个人消费者提供零件及手册</h2>
<p>苹果于2021年11月17日推出自助维修计划，该计划可向个人消费者提供有关零件、工具及维修手册。自助维修计划将会先从iPhone 12及iPhone 13产品开始，并将会在未来支持以M1芯片驱动的Mac电脑。此计划将率先在明年初于美国启动，并将会在2022年推广到其他国家。其初始阶段将会集中于如屏幕、电池、摄像头等最经常需要被维修的部件上，而其他维修部件将会于明年晚间的时候对外开放。苹果首席运营官Jeff Williams表示「进一步开放 Apple 原装零件的获取范围，将让我们的顾客在需要修理设备时拥有更多选择」且「在过去三年里，Apple 使可获取 Apple 原装零件、工具与培训的服务网点数目翻了近一番，现在我们将为那些希望自行完成维修的用户提供新的选项。」（引述Apple Newsroom消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/Apple_Self-Service-Repair_hero_11172021.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>在Apple Newsroom内与自助维修计划一起展示的海报。</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="英国利物浦发生自杀式炸弹袭击出租车司机将凶手锁在车内避免危机扩散">英国利物浦发生自杀式炸弹袭击，出租车司机将凶手锁在车内避免危机扩散</h2>
<p>一名来自叙利亚的难民Emad Al Swealmeen近日在英国周日的烈士纪念活动中策划自杀式炸弹恐怖袭击。Al Swealmeen在利物浦女子医院附近的一辆出租车内意外引爆了炸弹，的士司机David Perry在察觉到炸弹后迅速锁上车门并逃出。Al Swealmeen在车内引爆炸弹后当场死亡，而David Perry则收到轻伤。英国政府在恐袭发生之后将恐袭威胁水平提升至「严重」，而David Perry则得到来自政府人员以及群众的赞赏，且有部分群众为他发起捐款以帮助补偿他在爆炸中的损失。他的夫人称他能逃离爆炸「实属是一个奇迹」，且「他的周围必定有许多天使在守护着他」。（引述BBC Samantha Jagger消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0007/0_liverpool-womens-hospital5.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>爆炸之后David Perry的出租车。（经由Liverpool Echo）</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>免责声明：</em></p>
<p><em>所有新闻文章之选段之版权归于原作者、摄影师等作者及工作人员所有。本站呈现之新闻文章之选段并不代表本站同意之选段之立场及观点。</em></p>
<hr>
<p>关注我们以每周接收客观、准确的国际和国内新闻！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/08 ––– 2021/11/14]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211108-20211114/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211108-20211114/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-21T15:29:23.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>各位观众大家好！相信各位可能有看到之前发的一些英语新闻文章，这些文章是站长学校广播站新闻栏目的存档，所有的文章选段都由我采编，但原本的新闻稿就不是站长写的啦！在这里声明一下下。</p>
<p>从今天开始这个栏目会增加中文语言，如果各位喜欢的话可以考虑关注一下本站，如果不喜欢的话可以默默走开，井水不犯河水，楚河不犯汉界便是。本人小站经营也不易，所以也请各位观众高抬贵手，不开心就去看点开心的就行了 XD</p>
<p>因为这个是站长学校的广播电台的存档，所以为了隐私起见，任何有关校内的信息我全给删改了。<strong>⚠️如有熟人在底下留言泄露站长隐私的话，站长将会做删除评论处理。</strong></p>
<hr>
<h1 id="weekly-morning-newswire-20211108-20211114">Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/11/08 ––– 2021/11/14</h1>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, in today's Weekly Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>Facebook will delete its face-recognition system and delete more than 1 billion data.</li>
<li>U.S. House passed 1 Trillion Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, Biden claimed &quot;infrastructure week&quot;.</li>
<li>Hundreds migrants tried to storm Poland's border from Belarus.</li>
<li>Xi Jinping and Biden will hold video conference on November 16.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="facebook-will-delete-its-more-than-1-million-face-recognition-data-and-close-the-system">Facebook will delete its more than 1 million face-recognition data and close the system.</h2>
<p>Facebook announced that due to the potential misuses by the government and law-enforcement officials and the growing concerns from the public, they will shut down their face-recognition system and delete all the data, which contains faceprints  of over 1 million people. The vice president of artificial intelligence, Jerome Pesenti, for company Meta ––– the new parent company of Facebook, claimed that &quot;this change will represent one of the largest shifts in facial recognition usage in the technology’s history&quot;, and further said that company tries to balance between the positive use of technology and &quot;growing societal concerns, especially as regulators have yet to provide clear rules&quot;. (AP, Matt O'Brien and Barbara Ortutay)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>FILE - In this May 16, 2012, file photo, the Facebook logo is displayed on an iPad in Philadelphia. Facebook said it will shut down its face-recognition system and delete faceprints of more than 1 billion people. The unexpected announcement, Tuesday, Nov. 2, 2021, delivered with little fanfare in a blog post published, represents an abrupt about-face for the social network, which first launched use of the technology more than a decade ago. (AP Photo/Matt Rourke, File)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="biden-claimed-monumental-step-forward-as-the-house-of-representative-passed-the-1-trillion-bipartisan-infrastructure-bill-on-november-5">Biden claimed &quot;monumental step forward&quot; as the House of Representative passed the 1 trillion bipartisan infrastructure bill on November 5.</h2>
<p>The U.S. House of Representative passed the 1 trillion bipartisan bill for improving the infrastructure at last Friday (November 5) with 228 approvals and 208 vetoes. The legislation faced with the support from 13, mostly moderate, Republicans and opposition from 6 farthest-left Democrats. The U.S. President Joe Biden said that the Congress' passage as a &quot;monumental step forward for the nation&quot;. Biden happily told the reporters that it is an &quot;infrastructure week&quot;, and said that &quot;voters want us to deliver, and (Friday's vote) proved we can&quot;. (AP, Alan Fram and Zeke Miller)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-1.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>President Joe Biden speaks about the bipartisan infrastructure bill in the State Dinning Room of the White House, Saturday, Nov. 6, 2021, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="hundreds-or-thousands-immigrants-tried-to-storm-the-border-of-poland-facing-defense-from-polish-border-police">Hundreds or thousands immigrants tried to storm the border of Poland, facing defense from Polish border police.</h2>
<p>Numerous immigrants tried to get over the border of Poland from Belarus on Monday, throwing objects to the police and cutting the wire fences on the border. An armed Polish police officer was defensing the border by spraying to a woman who tries to cut the razor wire, and the immigrants have set up tents and stoves for settling near the border, according to the videos posted by the Defense Ministry of Poland. Some footages shot by Belarusian media show that some immigrants tried to get pass the border using the wooden poles and branches. The Interior Ministry of Poland said that they will take action against the illegal invasion and saying that the situation is under control. The spokesperson for Poland's security forces, Stanislaw Zaryn, claimed that &quot;a coordinated attempt to massively enter the territory of the Republic of Poland by migrants used by Belarus for the hybrid attacks against Poland has just begun&quot;. (AP, Monika Scislowska and Vanessa Gera)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-2.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Migrants from the Middle East and elsewhere gather at the Belarus-Poland border near Grodno, Belarus, Monday, Nov. 8, 2021. Poland increased security at its border with Belarus, on the European Union's eastern border, after a large group of migrants in Belarus appeared to be congregating at a crossing point, officials said Monday. The development appeared to signal an escalation of a crisis that has being going on for months in which the autocratic regime of Belarus has encouraged migrants from the Middle East and elsewhere to illegally enter the European Union, at first through Lithuania and Latvia and now primarily through Poland. (Leonid Shcheglov/BelTA via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-3.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Migrants from the Middle East and elsewhere rest on the ground as they gather at the Belarus-Poland border near Grodno, Belarus, Monday, Nov. 8, 2021. Poland increased security at its border with Belarus, on the European Union's eastern border, after a large group of migrants in Belarus appeared to be congregating at a crossing point, officials said Monday. The development appeared to signal an escalation of a crisis that has being going on for months in which the autocratic regime of Belarus has encouraged migrants from the Middle East and elsewhere to illegally enter the European Union, at first through Lithuania and Latvia and now primarily through Poland. (Leonid Shcheglov/BelTA via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="video-conference-between-xi-jinping-and-joe-biden-will-be-held-on-november-16">Video conference between Xi Jinping and Joe Biden will be held on November 16.</h2>
<p>Chinese National Chairman Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden will held a video conference on Tuesday (November 16), for &quot;exchanging agreements on the mutual concerns&quot;, according to Hua Chunying, the spokesperson for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of PRC. White House said that President Joe Biden will hold the meeting with Xi at Monday night of Eastern Standard Time, yet the officials pointed out that this conference &quot;might not achieve much progress&quot;. (Reuters, Lin Gaoli)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/mfa-pict.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The announcement of the video conference between Xi Jinping and Joe Biden, from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of PRC's website. (Screenshot by Micah S. Z.)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the ideas, meanings etc. that are presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="一周早间要闻-20211108-20211114">一周早间要闻 2021/11/08 ––– 2021/11/14</h1>
<p>各位观众早安！以下是这一周发生的要闻：</p>
<ul>
<li>脸书将关闭其人脸识别系统，并删除超过一百万个人脸数据。</li>
<li>美国国会通过万亿两党基建法案，拜登称这是一个「基建周」。</li>
<li>数百名难民试图从白俄罗斯跨越波兰边境。</li>
<li>习近平与拜登将于11月16日展开视讯会议。</li>
</ul>
<p>本站将从今天添加「一周早间要闻 Morning Newswire」的中文栏目，以为英语水平欠佳或非英语使用者的观众提供便利。</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="脸书将关闭其面部识别系统及其超过一百万条人脸数据">脸书将关闭其面部识别系统及其超过一百万条人脸数据</h2>
<p>因存在潜在的、可被政府及执法人员的隐私滥用及增长的公众担忧，脸书决定关停其面部识别系统及系统下的超过一百万的人脸数据。脸书新母公司Meta的人工智能副主席Jerome Pesenti称，此举将会是「在科技史上对面部识别使用的最大的转变」，且称公司将会于科技的正向使用与「日渐增长的社会忧虑、尤其是和监管者模糊不定的条例」之间作出平衡。（引述美联社Matt O'Brien和Barbara Ortutay消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>档案图 - 脸书的logo于2012年5月16日在费城的一台iPad上呈现。脸书称将会关停其人脸识别系统并删除系统下超过一百万的人脸数据。其于2021年11月2日在博客上推送的出乎意料且低调的通知代表了对这种10年之前就已经开始使用的人脸识别技术的一种突然转变。（美联社图/Matt Rourke，档案图）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="美国国会于11月5日通过两党万亿基建法案拜登称其为里程碑般的进步">美国国会于11月5日通过两党万亿基建法案，拜登称其为「里程碑般的进步」</h2>
<p>美国众议员于上周五（11月5日）以228赞成及208反对通过了两党万亿美元改进美国基础建设的法案，其中包含13名温和派共和党员的支持及6名极左翼民主党员的反对。美国总统乔·拜登称国会对法案的通过是「一个对国家里程碑般的进步」。他开心的告诉记者这是一个「基建周」并称「（周五的）投票证明了我们可以给选民们想要的」。（引述美联社Alan Fram和Zeke Miller消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="7"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-1.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>美国总统乔·拜登于2021年11月6日在华盛顿白宫国宴大厅谈论两党基建法案。（美联社图/Alex Brandon）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="数百名移民试图从白俄罗斯闯入波兰边境波兰警察进行防卫">数百名移民试图从白俄罗斯闯入波兰边境，波兰警察进行防卫</h2>
<p>成百上千名移民试图于本周一（11月8日）从白俄罗斯闯入波兰边境，并试图剪坏边境铁丝网及向警方投掷物体。据波兰国防部发布的视频显示，一名波兰武装警察朝正在破坏边境铁丝网的女子喷射化学喷雾，以及移民们正于边境旁安营扎寨以度过夜晚。据白俄罗斯媒体报道，一些移民尝试使用长木棍及木枝条越过波兰边境。波兰内政部称边境情况已得到控制，并将会采取行动制止对边境的非法侵入。一名波兰安全部队发言人Stanislaw Zaryn称「一场白俄罗斯在背后协调的、以使大量移民进入波兰共和国领土的对波兰的混合攻击已经开始了」。（引述美联社Monika Scislowska和Vanessa Gera消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="8"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-2.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>来自中东及别处的移民于2021年11月8日在白俄罗斯格罗德诺市附近的白俄波兰边境旁边聚集。据波兰官方称，波兰当局于大批移民聚集于突破口时在欧盟东部边境旁增加警力。这一事态发展似乎标志着一场持续了数月的危机的升级，白俄罗斯政权使得来自中东和其他地方的移民从最初的立陶宛和拉脱维亚，到现在主要通过波兰非法进入欧盟。（Leonid Shcheglov/BelTA 经由美联社）</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="9"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/1000-3.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>大批来自中东及别处的移民于2021年11月8日在白俄罗斯格罗德诺市旁的白俄波兰边境旁聚集，并坐在地上休息。据波兰官方称，波兰当局于大批移民聚集于突破口时在欧盟东部边境旁增加警力。这一事态发展似乎标志着一场持续了数月的危机的升级，白俄罗斯政权使得来自中东和其他地方的移民从最初的立陶宛和拉脱维亚，到现在主要通过波兰非法进入欧盟。（Leonid Shcheglov/BelTA 经由美联社）</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="习近平与拜登将于11月16日举行视频会晤">习近平与拜登将于11月16日举行视频会晤</h2>
<p>中国国家主席习近平及美国总统拜登将会于本周二（11月16日）举行视频会晤。中国外交部发言人华春莹称两国领导人将会「就中美关系和双方共同关心的问题交换意见」。白宫方面称总统乔·拜登将会于美东时间周一晚上与习近平进行视频会晤，但有官员指出此次会议「可能并不会取得太大成果」。（引述路透社林高丽消息）</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="10"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0006/mfa-pict.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>中国外交部对于中国国家主席习近平及美国总统乔·拜登举行视频会晤的通告。（Micah截图）</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>免责声明：</em></p>
<p><em>所有新闻文章之选段之版权归于原作者、摄影师等作者及工作人员所有。本站呈现之新闻文章之选段并不代表本站同意之选段之立场及观点。</em></p>
<hr>
<p>关注我们以每周接收客观、准确的国际和国内新闻！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/10/24 ––– 2021/10/31]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211024-20211031/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211024-20211031/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-21T15:24:53.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="weekly-morning-newswire-20211024-20211031">Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/10/24 ––– 2021/10/31</h1>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, in today's Weekly Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>Japanese princess Mako marries a commoner, giving up her loyal status.</li>
<li>Coup occurs in Sudan, PM of Sudan's transitional government was detained.</li>
<li>James Michael Tyler, actor for &quot;Gunther&quot; at series &quot;Friends&quot;, dies on October 24.</li>
<li>A deflagration incident occurred at an university in Nanjing, China.</li>
<li>Chinese audiences boycott the IMAX 3D format of the film &quot;Dune&quot;.</li>
<li>The United States issued the first passport with &quot;X&quot; gender marker.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="japanese-princess-mako-registered-marriage-with-kei-kumoro-losing-her-loyal-status">Japanese princess Mako registered marriage with Kei Kumoro, losing her loyal status.</h2>
<p>The niece of Japanese Emperor Naruhito, Mako Kumoro, recently registered marriage relationship on October 26 with Kei Kumoro, who has studied laws in the United States. Mako was required to give up her loyal status according to the Imperial Household Law of 1947 in Japan, which states that the Japanese Princess has to give up the loyal status when marrying to a male commoner. The couple will then move to New York to start a new life. (AP, Mari Yamaguchi)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/1000.jpeg" alt="1000" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Japan's former Princess Mako, right, the elder daughter of Crown Prince Akishino and Crown Princess Kiko, and her husband Kei Komuro, look at each other during a press conference to announce their marriage at a hotel in Tokyo, Japan Tuesday, Oct. 26, 2021. Former Princess Mako married the commoner and lost her royal status Tuesday in a union that has split public opinion after a three-year delay caused by a financial dispute involving her new mother-in-law. (Nicolas Datiche/Pool Photo via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="military-coup-takes-place-in-sudan-pm-of-sudan-was-arrested-and-security-forces-initiate-crackdown-towards-protesters">Military coup takes place in Sudan, PM of Sudan was arrested and security forces initiate crackdown towards protesters.</h2>
<p>A coup initiated by Sudan's military and its general, Gen. Abdel-Fattah Burhan, takes place on October 25, seizing power after arresting Sudan's Prime Minister, Abdalla Hamdok, of the current transitional government. Thousands of protesters walk on the streets for protesting military's interruption to the state's on-going progress to democracy, facing crackdown from the security powers. The crackdown results 3 deaths of and 80 demonstrators wounded, according to Sudan Doctors' Committee. Abdalla Hamdok and his wife were allowed to return home on October 26, according to an official statement from his office. (AP, Samy Magdy)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/1000-2.jpeg" alt="1000-2" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Pro-democracy protesters flash the victory sign as they take to the streets to condemn a takeover by military officials, in Khartoum, Sudan, Monday Oct. 25, 2021. Sudan’s military seized power Monday, dissolving the transitional government hours after troops arrested the acting prime minister and other officials. The takeover comes more than two years after protesters forced the ouster of longtime autocrat Omar al-Bashir and just weeks before the military was expected to hand the leadership of the council that runs the African country over to civilians. (AP Photo/Ashraf Idris)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="actor-for-gunther-at-the-series-friends-james-michael-tyler-dies-on-october-24">Actor for Gunther at the series &quot;Friends&quot;, James Michael Tyler, dies on October 24.</h2>
<p>The actor for the role Gunther, James Michael Tyler, dies on October 24 at the age of 59 after his 3-year long struggle with advance prostate cancer. The message was announced by James' manager Toni Benson. Tyler has become well known after casting in the popular series &quot;Friends&quot; as the role of Gunther, who is a server of the &quot;Central Perk&quot; coffeehouse and having an affection on another character Rachel. (AP)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/1000-3.jpeg" alt="1000-3" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>FILE - American actor James Michael Tyler poses for a portrait on Wednesday, Nov. 14, 2012, in New York. Tyler, the actor known widely for his recurring role as Gunther on “Friends,” died Sunday, Oct. 24, 2021, at his home in Los Angeles from prostate cancer. He was 59. (Photo by Carlo Allegri/Invision/AP, File)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="detonation-occurs-at-a-chinese-university-resulting-2-deaths-and-9-injured">Detonation occurs at a Chinese university, resulting 2 deaths and 9 injured.</h2>
<p>A deflagration occurs at a laboratory of the &quot;Jiangjun Building&quot; of the Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics on October 25, which might be caused by the inflation of chemicals. The building where the event occurs was just built at last year, and only a few chemicals and equipments were transported to that new building, according to an anonymous graduate student from this university. Some eyewitnesses claimed that they saw 2 students putting water on the staircase handrails to cool its temperature down for helping others to escape, and they are engulfed by the fire when the second detonation occurs. (Lianhe Zaobao)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/001NWzQDgy1gvra9kpim4j60u0140whj_e64b486b10184ad6be06c6d42e9e5cd1.jpg" alt="001NWzQDgy1gvra9kpim4j60u0140whj_e64b486b10184ad6be06c6d42e9e5cd1" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A deflagration incident occurs at a laboratory of NUAA, Nanjing, China on October 25. (Unknown Photographer)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="chinese-viewers-resist-dune-in-imax-3d-while-the-2d-version-is-still-on-the-way">Chinese viewers resist &quot;Dune&quot; in IMAX 3D, while the 2D version is still on the way.</h2>
<p>Chinese viewers went into outrage after they found out that the film &quot;Dune&quot; was presented in IMAX 3D without the option of 2D, and they decided to boycott the 3D format until the release of 2D at the cinema. Some claimed that it is not fair for the Chinese viewers only having limited choices compared to other countries' market, and some said that they will pirate the film instead for boycotting the 3D. Also they mentioned that seeing in 3D will distort the comfort when watching the movie. Yet while they are still holding their resistance, the 2D format was still not approve and release into the market yet. (variety.com)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/Dune-Movie-1.jpg.webp" alt="Dune-Movie-1.jpg" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A shot took from the film &quot;Dune&quot; by Denis Villeneuve. (via Warner Bros.)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="the-united-states-issued-the-first-passport-with-the-x-mark-on-the-gender-column">The United States issued the first passport with the &quot;X&quot; mark on the gender column.</h2>
<p>Dana Zzyym (pronounced Zimm), an intersex activist from Fort Collins, Colorado, recently received the first passport without stating the gender in the traditional dualistic type, but only with a &quot;X&quot; mark. Zzyym has been in a legal debate with the U.S. State Department for advocating the legalization of a third gender designation on the legal identifications, that Zzyym would not need to lie on the sexual identity. The State Department stated on October 27 that it is considered as &quot;a milestone in the recognition of the rights of people who do not identify as male or female, and expects to be able to offer the option more broadly next year&quot;. (AP, Colleen Slevin)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0004/1000-4.jpeg" alt="1000-4" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Dana Zzyym poses for a photo, Wednesday, Oct. 27, 2021, in Fort Collins, Colo. Zzyym, who prefers a gender-neutral pronoun, told the Associated Press that their passport is the first U.S. passport to be issued with an &quot;X&quot; gender designation, marking a milestone in the recognition of the rights of people who do not identify as male or female. (AP Photo/Thomas Peipert)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the ideas, meanings etc. that are presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/10/10 ––– 2021/10/16]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211010-20211016/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211010-20211016/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-21T15:19:53.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="weekly-morning-newswire-20211010-20211016">Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/10/10 ––– 2021/10/16</h1>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, in today's weekly Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>Murder occurs in Putian, Fujian Province due to household building dispute.</li>
<li>Overwhelming precipitation in Shanxi led to 15 deaths and 502 millions CNY loss.</li>
<li>Alibaba's founder, Jack Ma, reappears in Hong Kong, sources said.</li>
<li>&quot;Squid Game&quot; becomes the most successful series in Netflix.</li>
<li>Principal offender of SK's &quot;Nth Room Case&quot; was sentenced 42 years at final judgement.</li>
<li>Myanmar's military junta tries to hush Aung San Suu Kyi's lawyer, claiming his communications is &quot;unstable for the country&quot;.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="a-man-in-putian-murdered-2-and-hurt-3-due-to-possibly-household-building-injustices">A man in Putian murdered 2 and hurt 3 due to possibly household building injustices.</h2>
<p>Ou Jin Zhong, a man in Pinghai town at Putian, Fujian Province, murdered 2 and hurt 3 people, including a 10 year-old child. Sources claimed that the motive of Ou's murder is his request of the new construction of his house, which faced illegal halt from the neighbor. The local police offered a reward for capturing Ou, with 20000 CNY reward for the clue, and 50000 CNY for the discovery of his body.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/004e77pggy1gvd3vq97cbj60oo0gkjuu_e3fba36a7bd445c7861dcef3ecf3be48.jpg" alt="004e77pggy1gvd3vq97cbj60oo0gkjuu_e3fba36a7bd445c7861dcef3ecf3be48" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A picture of Ou's household (in the red ellipse) and the victim's household (in the red square).</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="15-are-dead-due-to-strong-precipitation-in-shanxi-causing-502-millions-cny-loss">15 are dead due to strong precipitation in Shanxi, causing 502 millions CNY loss.</h2>
<p>Shanxi's authority recorded the strongest autumn flood ever in record during the first week of October, and its aftermath has caused 15 deaths and 3 missing persons, with about 1.75 millions people affected, across 11 cities and 76 counties. (Xinhua News Agency)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/merlin_196129644_d2253f25-80df-42b6-87cf-741c8198126e-master1050.jpg" alt="merlin_196129644_d2253f25-80df-42b6-87cf-741c8198126e-master1050" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Photo via New York Times</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="jack-ma-reappears-in-hong-kong-sources-said">Jack Ma reappears in Hong Kong, sources said.</h2>
<p>Jack Ma, the Alibaba Group's founder, reappears in Hong Kong after he fade out of the public view due to the impact to his business last year, said by 2 sources who chose not to be identified. Jack has been keeping a low profile, after he gave the speech for criticizing the Chinese financial regulators last year at Shanghai. (Reuters)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/56DEIZI3VNPAFGDJ3IOAMKZUWU.jpg" alt="56DEIZI3VNPAFGDJ3IOAMKZUWU" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Jack Ma, founder and executive chairman of China's Alibaba Group, speaks in front of a picture of SoftBank's human-like robot named 'pepper' during a news conference in Chiba, Japan, June 18, 2015. (via REUTERS/Yuya Shino)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="squid-game-becomes-the-most-successful-netflix-series-with-111-millions-fans-within-a-month">&quot;Squid Game&quot; becomes the most successful Netflix series with 111 millions fans within a month.</h2>
<p>Netflix's original South Korean 9-episode thriller, &quot;Squid Game&quot; (오징어 게임), has become the most successful series of Netflix after its launch at a month ago, and officially received 111 millions fans, according to Netflix. The series describes a secret and dangerous contest which that &quot;hundreds of cash-strapped players accept a strange invitation to compete in children's games. Inside, a tempting prize awaits — with deadly high stakes.&quot; according to Netflix's description. (Reuters)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/AKZB47QKQ5PLRCZGMALKVS7VXY.jpg" alt="AKZB47QKQ5PLRCZGMALKVS7VXY" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A customer uses a tool to cut a biscuit into a shape during a session of a South Korean Netflix show Squid Game-themed confection-making event, at a bakery in Beijing, China in this screengrab from a video taken on October 16, 2021. (REUTERS TV via REUTERS)</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/15yNFmYA7IyOZF9x9i2vEOQ.jpeg" alt="15yNFmYA7IyOZF9x9i2vEOQ" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A poster of the series &quot;Squid Game&quot;. (via <a href="https://wall.alphacoders.com/big.php?i=1177222">the link here</a>)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="nth-room-cases-principal-offender-cho-ju-bin-was-sentenced-42-years-at-the-final-judgement">&quot;Nth Room&quot; case's principal offender, Cho Ju-bin, was sentenced 42 years at the final judgement.</h2>
<p>The master mind of South Korea's &quot;Nth Room&quot; (a.k.a. &quot;Doctor's Room&quot;, 박사방) case's mastermind, Cho Ju-bin (조주빈), was given 42 years of jail at the Supreme Court of Korea at October 14. He was accused of making illegal sexual contents and exploitation by threatening the victims, including children and adolescents, and was sentenced 40 years in jail in the trial at November last year. (Breaknews/브레이크뉴스)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/201125222117-cho-joo-bin-file-super-tease.jpg" alt="201125222117-cho-joo-bin-file-super-tease" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A picture of Cho Ju-bin. (via CNN)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="lawyer-of-the-former-myanmars-leader-aung-san-suu-kyi-was-said-given-hush-from-myanmars-junta">Lawyer of the former Myanmar's leader Aung San Suu Kyi was said given hush from Myanmar's junta.</h2>
<p>Khin Maung Zaw, the head lawyer representing Aung San Suu Kyi, was given restrictions by the junta on speaking to media, diplomats, international organizations and foreign governments, according to his Facebook post. The junta authorities have made a reply, claiming that his communications &quot;may cause harassment, hurting a person who is acting in accordance with the law, may cause riots and destabilise the public peace&quot;, and claiming that &quot;some local and foreign media outlets, illegal media outlets and the media are inciting fake information that could destabilise the country.&quot; (Reuters)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="7"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0002/5TBIMAB66JNWLLTMFLE3BRZNHI.jpg" alt="5TBIMAB66JNWLLTMFLE3BRZNHI" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Myanmar State Counselor Aung San Suu Kyi delivers a speech to the nation over Rakhine and Rohingya situation, in Naypyitaw, Myanmar September 19, 2017. (via REUTERS/Soe Zeya Tun/File Photo)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the ideas, meanings etc. that are presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekly Morning Newswire 2021/10/01 ––– 2021/10/10]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211001-20211010/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-morning-newswire-20211001-20211010/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-11-20T16:42:50.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good morning to all English speakers! This is an entire new column for the site, and it is also an archive for the newswires I wrote for the campus. Please enjoy !!! 😃</p>
<hr>
<p>Good morning from Shenzhen, In this week's Morning Newswire:</p>
<ul>
<li>China celebrates its 72th anniversary, while China's ex-minister of the Ministry of Justice is investigated for indiscipline.</li>
<li>Around 700,000 Americans died from Covid-19 as the cases are dropping.</li>
<li>Fumio Kishida becomes the new P.M. of Japan after Yoshihide Suga declared to quit of re-election in September.</li>
<li>The Nobel Prize awarding Institutions unveil the result of the 2021 Nobel Prize.</li>
<li>A Russian film crew is making a new film, in space.</li>
<li>Texas SB 8 abortion ban was temporarily halted by the Court.</li>
<li>China urges for peaceful reunions with Taiwan, receiving strong feedback from Tsai Ing-Wen.</li>
<li>A 100-year old ex-Nazi SS guard went on trial as the oldest person to be tried.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="china-holds-72th-founding-anniversary-and-investigations-to-the-ex-minister-of-the-ministry-of-justice">China holds 72th founding anniversary, and investigations to the ex-minister of the Ministry of Justice.</h2>
<p>China and the Chinese people stepped into its 72th anniversary and a 7-day holiday, with packed and overwhelming tourists at nearly all the attractions across the country. Meanwhile, the former minister of the Ministry of Justice, Fu Zhenghua, was involved into series of investigations due to his &quot;severe misconduct&quot;, according to the State Committee of Supervisory of PRC. The Ministry of Justice and Beijing Public Security Bureau stated their strict attitude on similar inappropriate behaviors, after a meeting held in October 2. (Caixin)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/16332725719339.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A portrait of Fu Zhenghua. (via Caixin)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="us-exceeds-700000-covid-19-death-tolls-as-the-cases-drops">U.S. exceeds 700,000 Covid-19 Death Tolls, as the cases drops.</h2>
<p>The United States arrives at the total 700,000 Covid-19 deaths from 600,000, which is larger than the population of Boston, with a short period of 3 and a half months. The vast unvaccinated people who are qualified to get the vaccine shots was regarded as the main reason for the spreading of the virus, and the increasingly rising death toll, according to the public health leaders and medical professionals. The U.S. President's chief medical advisor, Dr. Anthony Fauci, warned on Friday that seeing a decreasing trend is not a reason to remain unvaccinated. (NPR)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/16332389870298.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The data on Covid-19 of the United States of America, screenshot at 2021/10/03 --- 1:30 p.m.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="fumio-kishida-becomes-the-new-pm-of-japan-after-becoming-the-president-of-japan-ldp">Fumio Kishida becomes the new P.M. of Japan, after becoming the president of Japan LDP.</h2>
<p>Japan's former foreign minister, Fumio Kishida, becomes the president of the Japan Liberal-Democratic Party by defeating his opponent, Kono Taro, with 257 votes from the party members. Kishida will replace the current prime minister, Yoshihide Suga, who chose to step down due to the overwhelming criticisms to his Covid-19 response. Kishida officially becomes the P.M. of Japan after an election held in Japan's parliament at October 4. He also claimed more strategies for coping the Covid-19 and strengthening the bond with like-minded allies for against Beijing's administration over its rising tension with Hong Kong and Taiwan. (AP, NPR)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/1000.jpeg" alt="1000" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Fumio Kishida bows after being elected as Japan's prime minister at the parliament's lower house Monday, Oct. 4, 2021, in Tokyo. Kishida was formally elected Monday as Japan's new prime minister in a parliamentary vote, replacing Yoshihide Suga. (via AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="the-2021-nobel-prize-results-were-announced-by-the-awarding-institutions">The 2021 Nobel Prize Results were announced by the awarding institutions.</h2>
<p>The results were presented below in the releasing time order. Sources are from the site <a href="nobelprize.org">nobelprize.org</a>.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left">Awarding Subject</th>
<th style="text-align:left"><strong>Laureates</strong> &amp; <em>Affiliation</em></th>
<th style="text-align:left"><u>Motivation</u></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Physiology or Medicine</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>David Julius</strong> <em>(University of California, San Francisco, CA, USA)</em> &amp; <strong>Ardem Patapoutian</strong> <em>(Howard Hughes Medical Institute)</em></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><u>For their discoveries of receptors for temperature and touch</u></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Physics</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>Syukuro Manabe</strong> <em>(Princeton University, Princeton, NJ, USA)</em> &amp; <strong>Klaus Hasselmann</strong> <em>(Max Planck Institute for Meteorology, Hamburg, Germany)</em> &amp; <strong>Giorgio Parisi</strong> <em>(Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy)</em></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><u>For the physical modelling of Earth's climate, quantifying variability and reliably</u> (Manabe &amp; Hasselmann) &amp; <u>For the discovery of the interplay of disorder and fluctuations in physical systems from atomic to planetary scales</u> (Parisi)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Chemistry</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>Benjamin List</strong> <em>(Max-Planck-Institut für Kohlenforschung, Mülheim an der Ruhr, Germany)</em> &amp; <strong>David W.C. MacMillian</strong> <em>(Princeton University, Princeton, NJ, USA)</em></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><u>For the development of asymmetric organocatalysis</u></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Literature</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>Abdulrazak Gurnah</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><u>For his uncompromising and compassionate penetration of the effects of colonialism and the fate of the refugee in the gulf between cultures and continents</u></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Peace</td>
<td style="text-align:left"><strong>Maria Ressa</strong> &amp; <strong>Dmitry Muratov</strong></td>
<td style="text-align:left"><u>For their efforts to safeguard freedom of expression, which is a precondition for democracy and lasting peace</u></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The Nobel Prize of Economic Sciences will be released in October 11, 2021 by The Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, according to the press release of NobelPrize.org.</p>
<h2 id="a-russian-film-crew-took-their-film-shots-at-international-space-station">A Russian film crew took their film shots at International Space Station.</h2>
<p>The director Klim Shipenko and the actor Yulia Pereslid move the shooting scenes of their movie, &quot;The Challenge&quot;, to the International Space Station in a Russian Soyuz spacecraft, with the accompany of a cosmonaut Anton Shkaplerov. Their spacecraft took off at 08:55 GMT from Baikonur, Kazakhstan, and arrived at the station after about 3 and a half hours. The crew planned to return to Earth with an another cosmonaut after 12 days of stay. The mission was said that it will be an effective propaganda to Russia's space powers and history, according to the Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov. (AP)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/1000-2.jpeg" alt="1000-2" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>In this photo taken from video footage released by Roscosmos Space Agency, actress Yulia Peresild, left, film director Klim Shipenko, right, and cosmonaut Anton Shkaplerov sit in the first row among other participants of the mission in the International Space Station, ISS, Tuesday, Oct. 5, 2021. Russian actress Yulia Peresild and a film director Klim Shipenko rocketed to space Tuesday on a mission to make the world's first movie in orbit, a project the Kremlin said will help burnish the nation's space glory. (Roscosmos Space Agency via AP)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="texas-abortion-ban-was-halted-by-federal-judge-claiming-unlawfully-prevented-womens-constitutional-rights">Texas abortion ban was halted by federal judge, claiming &quot;unlawfully prevented women's Constitutional rights&quot;.</h2>
<p>The new Texan SB 8 abortion law was halted by a federal judge after the Department of Justice sued Texas for its unconstitutional accusations and the impact brought by the new law, which caused massive shutdown of the abortion clinics due to their consternations of being sued. The SB 8 abortion law stated the prohibition to abortion after 6 weeks of pregnancy, even from unintentional means like rape, sexual abuse, incest etc. U.S. District Court Judge Robert Pitman said that &quot;women have been unlawfully prevented from exercising control over their lives in ways that are protected by the Constitution&quot; after the law has went into effect last month. He also stated that &quot;......This Court will not sanction one more day of this offensive deprivation of such an important right&quot;. U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland commented on court's decision as &quot;a victory for women in Texas and for the rule of law&quot;, and claims that &quot;it is the foremost responsibility of the Department of Justice to defend the Constitution&quot;. (NPR)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/16337952948672.jpg" alt="16337952948672" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Protesters take part in the Women's March and Rally for Abortion Justice at the State Capitol in Austin, Texas, on Saturday. (Sergio Flores/AFP via Getty Images)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="china-propose-peaceful-reunion-with-taiwan-receiving-strong-feedback-from-tsai-ing-wen">China propose &quot;peaceful reunion&quot; with Taiwan, receiving strong feedback from Tsai Ing-Wen.</h2>
<p>Chinese President Xi Jinping proposed &quot;peaceful reunion&quot; with Taiwan at Oct 9, claiming that the Chinese people &quot;have a glorious tradition of opposing separatism&quot;, and &quot;Taiwan independence separatism is the biggest obstacle to achieving the reunification of the motherland, and the most serious hidden danger to national rejuvenation&quot;, after a breaking-record amount of PLA flights flew by Taiwan in the recent week. The Tsai Ing-Wen administration posed a firm response to Beijing, stating that &quot;only Taiwan's people can decide its future&quot; and they &quot;will not compromise on defending its (Taiwan's) sovereignty or freedom&quot;. (Reuters)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/W2PN2TILWRI2ZI2R2COIRKOCGM.jpg" alt="W2PN2TILWRI2ZI2R2COIRKOCGM" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Tsai Ing-wen attends a gala on the eve of Taiwan's National Day at Hsinchu Air Force Base in Hsinchu, Taiwan October 9, 2021. (via REUTERSN/Ann Wang)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="a-100-year-old-ex-nazi-ss-guard-was-tried-in-a-court-in-brandenburg-germany">A 100-year old ex-Nazi SS guard was tried in a court in Brandenburg, Germany.</h2>
<p>Josef Schuetz, an ex-Nazi SS guard who worked at the Sachsenhausen concentration camp in Oranienburg, north of Berlin, was tried in a court in Germany with the accusation of assisting of murdering 3518 criminals. Josef is 100-year old on the trial, and he is the oldest person be against on a trial for the Nazi-era crimes. He remains free during the trial and he will be less likely to be put in jail due to his age. Leon Schwarzbaum, a holocaust survivor, said that he wishes this man to be put in jail if he was found guilty. (AFP, Reuters)</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="7"><img src="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post-images/media/0001/FM7YCMQU2FMALAPNJJTMXV6EPE.jpg" alt="FM7YCMQU2FMALAPNJJTMXV6EPE" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A 100-year-old former security guard of the Sachsenhausen concentration camp appears in the courtroom before his trial at the Landgericht Neuruppin court in Brandenburg, Germany, October 7, 2021. (via REUTERS/Annegret Hilse)</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclaimer:</em></p>
<p><em>All the copyrights of the journal excerpts belong to the original authors, photographers etc. By presenting the excerpts do not mean we endorse or object the idea, meaning etc. presented in the excerpts. The opinions in the excerpt do not represent the site's opinion.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Follow us to receive the objective, accurate world and domestic news every week!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[为河南祈福&更新通知]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/pray-for-henan/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/pray-for-henan/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-07-24T16:50:25.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这几日发生在中原大地上的人间惨剧，相信各位都有目共睹。</p>
<p>如果各位读者点进了这篇文章，站长恳请你抽出一分钟的时间，为现在在河南的每一位正在受苦的人祈福，也希望为每一位不幸逝世的人默哀。</p>
<p>站长在洪水爆发的前夕到访过河南，并被那里雄厚的历史以及热情友好的本地人打动。</p>
<p>现在，我们在这片土地上见到了失去至亲的悲痛，<strong>也有在一个个人之中展现的舍小我为大义的勇气。</strong></p>
<p><em><strong>这些人的精神堪比钻石，他们的光辉将比肩繁星。</strong></em></p>
<hr>
<p>站长本来计划从河南回来时更新博文，讲一下自己的游记。</p>
<p>但我刚刚离开的时候暴雨就开始倾入，并造成了一系列惨剧。</p>
<p>看到了许许多多惨痛的后果之后，以及加上站长本人的一点不勤快，<strong>站长觉得在发生灾难之时更新游记不是非常妥当，所以决定将河南游记无限期延更，直至灾情过去之时。</strong></p>
<p>河南是一个美妙的地方，五天的游览给站长带来了很多美好的回忆。只希望灾情能够尽快过去，我们在那时候也能一起分享河南之行的喜悦。</p>
<hr>
<p>在最后，站长想给各位分享一首歌曲，歌名叫Come Healing，歌手名为Elayna Boynton，下图为专辑封面：</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><a href="https://imgtu.com/i/WcX5ee"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/07/25/WcX5ee.jpg" alt="WcX5ee.jpg" loading="lazy"></a></figure>
<p>这首歌曲曾被用为王子逸导演的电影《别告诉她》的主题曲，电影讲述了一个亲情的故事，有兴趣的读者可以自行寻找观看。</p>
<p>这首歌里面站长最喜欢的是它的音调，以及它的歌词，十分建议看着歌词一起听。</p>
<p>希望这首歌，不论被谁听到，也不论你在不在灾区中央，都能给你带来抚摸，使你的心灵重归平静。</p>
<p>愿天佑河南，以及每一位受苦受难的人。</p>
<p>也感谢所有对河南表示支持及关切的个人，企业，以及外国政府。</p>
<p>最重要的，<strong>感谢每一位在救援中奉献了自己力量的人。</strong></p>
<p>阿门🙏🙏🙏🕯🕯🕯</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[想体验被世界丢弃的感觉，只需要丢掉你身上唯一一只口罩]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/lost-only-mask-feel-so-lonely/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/lost-only-mask-feel-so-lonely/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-07-24T16:41:23.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今日节气正值大暑，在看了看天气，知道了现在整个广州都是个大空气炸锅的事实之后，站长我就突然决定出门转转，安放心情。</p>
<p>在长寿东路坚记面店一顿完美的牛腩捞伊面，以及一个看起来不会下雨偷袭我这个老同志的天气，让我产生了这将会是完美的一天的暂时性错觉。</p>
<p>坐车抵达了珠江新城，并横跨了海心桥走过了广州塔然后又转回来最后坐在公园长椅上休息的天真的我，还没有意识到生活给我精心设计了一场荒诞戏剧。</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://gitee.com/drclairvoyant/picgo-picbed/raw/master/IMG_20210722_154141.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>途中路过美国驻广州总领事馆</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://gitee.com/drclairvoyant/picgo-picbed/raw/master/DSC01766.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>桥上拍的，不知道为什么上个桥还要预约，你不就一给人走的桥吗</p>
</blockquote>
<p>当我已经歇息足够，起身出发找点喝的并已经走到商场门口时，我把手往裤兜里一摸，结果空空如也～</p>
<p>在我的大脑短暂空白了一两秒后，我才意识到<strong>我的口罩竟然丢了！！！</strong></p>
<p>悲剧了，流泪了，此时我站在暖风中一阵凌乱。</p>
<p>处在一个被各种钢铁高楼CBD围绕的城市中心，渺小的我竟然感受到了一种如同在大街上裸奔的无地自容。</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><a href="https://imgtu.com/i/WcTYjJ"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/07/24/WcTYjJ.png" alt="WcTYjJ.png" loading="lazy"></a></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>跟老白差不多</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在意识到了这个残酷的现实过后，站长秉承着“人总不至于站着饿死”的精神，去到旁边寻找可能的免费口罩。</p>
<p>既然身处在珠江新城–––广州的市中心，这么先进繁华的地方，又离广州塔这个大景点这么近，总不至于连一个口罩都没有吧？</p>
<p>毕竟离广州塔这么近，基本上等于这里会是游客常来的地方，而这些地方都会有提供服务的游客中心。果不其然，走几步路就碰上了党群服务中心，而且有四个，于是站长遂逐个进入要口罩……</p>
<p>结果四个里面一个都没有。</p>
<p>那时我甚至有些怀疑我是不是某种地球无性繁殖出来的某种生物，连点地球妈妈的爱都享受不到，只觉得往脸上吹的暖风更劲了些。</p>
<p>四个党群服务中心兼游客中心，急救包你容得下，AED你容得下，墙上满满的党史你也容得下，但怎么就容不下一个小小的口罩呢？</p>
<p>站长当时一时不知道如何是好，因为即使没带口罩进不去商场，你连公交车和地铁都上不去！</p>
<p>似乎唯一的出路就只能是招个的士打道回府，正当我准备承认口罩这小伙子不跟我这老同志讲武德的时候，我的眼神突然转向了一个方向，一间便利店。</p>
<p>便利店！对啊，即使游客服务中心碰巧没有，但是便利店基本上都有口罩的啊！</p>
<p>于是我走近店面，<strong>摆在货架上的口罩和温和的售货员大妈正在对我闪耀着爱的光辉。</strong></p>
<p>买了口罩并戴上了之后，我想出了一句话：</p>
<blockquote>
<p>健康码是衣服，而口罩则是我们的内裤。</p>
<p>––– 站长</p>
</blockquote>
<p>不过美中不足的是，卖的口罩没有分装只有合装，就是五六个口罩装在了一起的那种，但是也至少总比没有好。</p>
<p>走在街上，脸上带着一个口罩，手里又拿着一包口罩，感觉像是战场被一颗子弹打中之后，而对火力不足产生了恐惧。</p>
<p>就好比可能别人都只拿一把步枪踏上战场，而我则是双持了两个重型机枪。</p>
<hr>
<p>解决完晚饭，夜色降临大地，站长也在回程的公交车思考了一番。</p>
<p>虽然现在我们人人都已经养成了出门做好充足防疫要求的习惯，但是即使在大多数人养成了习惯的同时，我们也需要考虑到多个应急预案和小概率情况。</p>
<p>就像即使一栋大楼里边人人都不会去玩火，可都还是要备好灭火器和消防水管一样。</p>
<p>这次虽然在四个党群服务中心都没有拿到口罩，但是有一说一，每一个都配备了AED和急救物品，这个也是值得表扬的。</p>
<p>只不过，站长在这里也由衷的希望，情况也可以考虑的更加全面一点点。就像大多数人不会丢口罩，我们大多数时候也可能碰不到别人心脏骤停需要我们急救的情况，但是我们也都需要配备好如AED的所有的应对措施。</p>
<p>那这里AED有了，口罩是不是也可以考虑一下呢？</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[解释一下我的名字]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/my-aliases/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/my-aliases/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-07-03T18:53:47.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>有些人可能看到这个博客会感到有些奇怪，不是说是叫「Micah的日常BB Channel」吗？那你这网址域名里的「drclairvoyant」又是什么意思？</p>
<p>其实Micah是我自己平常使用的一个英语名，是《圣经》里面一位先知的名字。这个名字是我的一位小学校长给我起的，而Dr_Clairvoyant其实是我另外一个虚拟名称（既是网名也是笔名）。</p>
<p>用了clairvoyant这个词是我一开始看了神盾局特工第一季的时候有一个反派好像叫「千里眼」，英语名就叫clairvoyant，当时觉得这个单词逼格过高于是就作为己用了。我也有想过把这个单词中译，单纯中译的话就叫「千里眼」，但我个人觉得不太好听，于是就想了「老千」这个名字。</p>
<p><s>当然这个和作弊出猫的那个老千不是一个东西啊</s></p>
<p>那有些聪明帅气的读者可能就问了说「啊那这样的话你为什么不叫“老千的日常BB Channel”啊？」，我一开始也纠结过这个问题，后面决定用Micah是因为这个名字对我来说也更亲近一点，而且也没有老千这个词本身带有的歧义😋</p>
<p>不过在这里你们用上面的任何一个名字呼叫本站长也没有任何问题！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【一周BB】2021/06/28–––2021/07/04]]></title>
        <id>https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-bb-20210628-20210704/</id>
        <link href="https://drclairvoyant.github.io/post/weekly-bb-20210628-20210704/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-07-02T03:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>2021年06月28日</strong><br>
坐在星巴克，隔壁有一对母子，妈妈给儿子在教什么心室、动脉、哪里在哪里等等，还说等会要画图考他；这孩子看着还差不多初中，要学医也太早了点吧？</p>
<p>几分钟后更新一下，我仔细的看了一下他们手上的纸，估计是学人体生物学到心脏和血管这一块了。想想以前也学过但是现在全还给老师了，自叹自愧不如。但我真怕那个儿子少秃头，还挺帅的一小伙子，可别这么早就把头发奉献了。</p>
<p><strong>2021年06月28日</strong></p>
<p>博客用的是GitHub Pages，换了三个网挂了梯子同步都不行，但是换了第二个网没有挂梯子就行了</p>
<p>？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？？</p>
<p>GFW啊GFW，你总是能给我搞出点新花样（</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>2021年06月29日</strong><br>
看到有一个美国和澳大利亚的研究，说20000年以前就有过冠状病毒大流行了，突然之间就有了一个恐怖的脑洞：会不会新冠病毒就是自然的产物，用以定点清除及灭绝人类，以维持自身的生态平衡；后面在我们灭绝后（只是一个假设哈，脑洞嘛想啥都行），新的人类物种诞生，进化了好久后又被新一轮的冠状病毒灭绝？</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>2021年07月02日</strong><br>
早上8:30起来，放了一个有低频下潜的屁。</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月02日</strong><br>
麻了，同步个博客就跟排雷似的，每一次同步还得看连哪个网要不要挂梯子，给我快整分裂了都。</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月02日</strong><br>
学多邻国的拉丁语课程发现个挺有意思的点：拉丁语在翻译「纽约」这个外来词的时候是直译，就是把New York一个一个词的翻译成Novum（New） Eboracum（York），还挺好玩的；如果放到中文上面的话就是把New York直接翻译成「新乡」，把Mont Blanc翻译成「长白山」。</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月02日</strong><br>
转自QQ空间，原文作者@踏伞：</p>
<p>一些人奇怪的政治冷感：</p>
<p>在看到言论自由/婚姻&amp;生育&amp;劳动保障相关话题的讨论/lgtbq+&amp;女权时表示自己不想关心新闻时事，不支持不在乎不赞同不反对任何政治观点，只想过与政治无关的平静生活</p>
<p>在一些主旋律节日转发***领导人肖像进行祈福并高呼万岁</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>2021年07月03日</strong><br>
想对索尼发布会与七七事变“撞车”说几句，其实绝大多数人的反感估计都是觉得索尼专挑这一天来开发布会，是“有意的碰瓷”，觉得日本人不和我们在这一天痛哭流涕是一种罪过，但如果就只是开了个发布会跟日期刚好装上你都还要抵制日货，那你这心理承受能力也太差了。</p>
<p>我们作为新一代，国耻自然是不能忘记，但同时也应该具有良好的文化自信能力。这种自信能力不是体验在穿着中华传统服饰上街不顾旁人的眼光就完事的了，而是在纪念其他民族对自身民族造成的苦难时保持良好平和的态度严肃正视历史问题。谁说遇到这种事的时候就一定要以得了甲亢一般的怒气相待了？</p>
<p>要是以纯粹的愤怒来应对，并同时指责别人为什么不跟其他愤怒的人一样愤怒的话，恐怕会有更多的人，脑袋被U型锁砸破，然后落得一身残疾。</p>
<p>再给一些真的不想作深度思考的人写点小拓展：上面说的“良好平和的态度”不是要你把对方当爷，像宠着贵妃一样好生伺候，而是在即使对方是以前的敌国的时候也能保持基本的礼数和尊敬。这种概念可能有些人会说“我们为什么要和一个以前的敌人友好”？如果这么想的话再想想为什么现在的中国与日本建交了，而且两国之间还有政府出资的文化交流？你也可以把事情做绝，现在就跑去日本驻华大使馆抽日本驻华大使一耳光，但是之后的结果你可得考虑清楚，万一真因为你的一耳光日本人决定和中国断交了也不是完全不可能的事。</p>
<p>我们要抵制的是这种法西斯军国主义以及以前对平民百姓下手的侩子手，而不是现在与以前的历史罪行毫无瓜葛的平民以及无辜的商品（有些商品虽然说是日本品牌，可也都还是中国生产，你坑的最直接的可能都是我们工人同胞），你要是一个日本人，看见一个中国人骂你罪恶多端，用上了各种粗口脏话，而他骂你的原因却都是一些你出生之前的事，你内心还会想和这个人或者是这个民族保持良好的关系吗？</p>
<p>以前二战的时候，德国纳粹党的威力震慑全欧洲，然后到最后也落得一个战败的下场。美国、苏联和欧洲多个国家都参与了战争，也没见他们之后对改组之后的德国政府和大使拳打脚踢。不过一战战后的时候英国、法国和意大利（这三国家里两个是协约国，跟德国打仗也被打得重）都也怀揣着“为什么不严厉惩戒德国”的小九九对战后的德国拳打脚踢，于是踢着踢着就踢了个二战出来（希特勒就是靠着极端的民族主义上台的）。</p>
<p>个人拙见而已，各位若感无趣，一笑划走便是🙏🙏🙏</p>
<p>（后面才想起来，要是把索尼赶走了，你们手机的相机cmos怎么办？倒是可以用三星，但是之前你们也不是一个个骂“高丽棒子”骂得挺凶的吗？）</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月03日</strong><br>
Minecraft国际版（Java）继支持了世界上绝大多数语言之后又来了个<strong>文言文版！</strong> 有一些字词翻译的还挺有意思的。Minecraft可能是我见过的游戏之中支持世界上最多的语言的游戏了，这次要是把文言文版搞好应该也挺有文化传承的一种意义的。</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>2021年07月04日</strong><br>
中午逛街，下午回来睡着了，现在晚上睡不着了……</p>
<p>我这造的什么孽啊……</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月04日</strong><br>
转载自微博网友@MebiuW（<mark>荧光色为本人言论</mark>）：</p>
<p>回想一下现在的互联网出现了多少倒退呢？</p>
<p>1、比如说很多服务的网页版、桌面端被陆续遗弃，甚至关停。<mark>电脑打字不舒服吗？</mark></p>
<p>2、很多原来有的Web服务，渐渐的变成离开了手机APP就没法用，比如说今天吐槽的网易云音乐的登录。<mark>微信电脑版你赶紧给我出来挨两巴</mark></p>
<p>3、每一个集团自己圈了一个圈子，很难从一个圈子访问到另一个圈子。 在过去，你有问题，你可能只需要在搜索引擎中搜一下，点一下就好。 现在轻则是你搜一下，跳转到它的APP，重则是你需要一个APP一个APP的去搜索。</p>
<p>4、比如我在一个平台看到一个好看的视频，好用的东西，如果我在这个平台没和我朋友好友，那么我和他分享都很难。 比如微博发个外链可能发布出去，比如微信直接给你吞了，etc...</p>
<p>不可否认现在的技术发展让生活便利了很多，但也不能否认现在各家的各自圈地也在很多地方把体验搞得越来越差。</p>
<p><strong>2021年07月04日</strong><br>
刚看完罗小黑第38集，怎么现在连罗小黑也开始刀了</p>
<p>坏耶</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>